Ronaldo Lopez-Muro

El Paso, TX | ronnielopezmuro@gmail.com | +1 (915) 219-1461 | linkedin.com/in/ronaldolopezmuro |github.com/ronniemuro

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

As a web developer with a background in healthcare and education, I bring a drive for continual learning and strengths in problem solving, communication, and collaboration to writing code. My experience working with students and patients translates to a passion for improving the user experience and creating technical solutions that make people's lives easier.

SKILLS

Technical: Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, APIs, Pair-Programming, TDD,

Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap

Additional: Spanish (native fluent)

EDUCATION

Actualize | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Mar. 2022 - Jul. 2022

- Capstone Project (Synastry): personally built a web app where people can connect based on their astrological signs. Built with a Ruby on Rails backend and Vue.js frontend, the app allows users to interact in a social media style format and update based on either their sun, moon, or rising. This app integrates a third party API for profile photo uploads.
- **Bootcamp:** Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
 - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
 - Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
 - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes

El Paso Community College | General Coursework (One semester) in Fashion Design

Fall 2020

The University of Texas at El Paso | Bachelors of Science in Biological Sciences, Biomedical Concentration

Spring 2020

Graduated Summa Cum Laude

EXPERIENCE

North American Language and Culture Assistants Program | Language Assistant

Sep. 2021 - June 2022

- Taught English, Biology, Chemistry and Physics to classes of up to 30 students in grades 7-12
- Evaluated English speaking and grammar proficiency of over 200 students in preparation for their English certification tests

GET Marketing | Mac Specialist Consultant

Jun. 2021 - Sep. 2021

Increased Apple product sales by \$2,000 a day by assisting customers with product information and special discounts

University of Texas at El Paso - College of Health Sciences | COVID-19 Case Investigator

Feb. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Assessed patient symptoms and tracked their recent contacts in order to mitigate the spread of COVID 19
- Recorded patient data in internal system with careful attention to detail to track public health conditions

ScribeAmerica | Emergency Room Medical Scribe

September 2019 - February 2021

- Documented all aspects of patients' interactions with ER doctor quickly and accurately, creating over 600 detailed and organized electronic medical records
- Provided translation assistance between doctors and patients, facilitating smooth communication across English and
 Spanish language barriers and ensuring appropriate care
- Communicated lab and radiology results with medical staff to determine next steps for patient treatment

YWCA El Paso del Norte Region | STEAM Tutor

February 2019 - February 2020

• Created and led fun and engaging STEAM related activities for groups of up to 25 students in afterschool programs based on their grade level and available resources

NIH-funded SmartMind program at UTEP | Research Intern

May 2019 - August 2019

- Conducted neuroscience related research with hands-on experiments to analyze results for genetic deficiency project
- Collaborated with research mentor and lab members, acquiring and practicing analytical skills and fundamental knowledge in neuroscience